we've been talking about a well-known
person you like or admire and I'd like
to discuss with you one or two more
general questions related to this let's
consider first of all famous people in
your country so in Malaysia what kind of
people become famous um in Malaysia
definitely the politicians and also some
actors and actresses are very famous
among the among Malaysians uh so what
about in the past is that the same as in
the past were were politicians and
actors and actresses always I think
definitely in the past if you're talking
about the ' 50s and 60s um movies were
the number one communication tool
between Villages or towns so the people
definitely knew actors and actresses
better than the politicians compared to
now you have TV and news where people
follow politicians personal life more
than an actor or actress because in many
cultures quite the opposite has happened
where politicians used to be quite well
known whereas nowadays movie stars
television stars are more welln what do
you think about in the future do you
think that that's going to continue
politicians will continue to be I think
definitely in the future because the
world is becoming more globalized
Malaysians would have a I think have a
tendency
to be exposed to more International
programs and they know more
International celebrities compared to
the local actors and actresses or local
politicians so we would follow
International politics maybe American or
British politics or even the models or
actresses
internationally well let's talk about
celebrity culture often famous people
are used in advertisements can you give
me some examples of that yeah um famous
people like actors and actresses are
used in advert
advertisements and um as especially
Sports celebrities like Tiger Woods or
Roger fedra promoting sports equipment
or sports shoes or clothes um other than
that I think it's more models and
actresses that sponsor perfume and
clothes and and is that always true that
um whatever profession they're involved
in that's the kind of product that they
tend to promote I don't think that's
true because a lot of um celebrity
actresses
support perfumes and support clothes
where whereby actually it should be
models that do it but isn't that that
sort of glamorous kind of side of
Hollywood that they can try to bring to
the public I suppose that's what they're
trying to do the marketing the the
people who are marketing the product are
trying to bring in the glamour that the
that that celebrity
holds um but yeah I suppose a celebrity
do they do have that that grasp over you
know people's mindset and what they
should buy the
consumerism now you're talking about
their influence on the consumer what
about on the young um do celebrities do
you think produce negative effects in in
our youth definitely I think they do as
you can see like lifestyle and health
you know celebrities are becoming
thinner models and celebrities and when
you open a magazine young girls would be
exposed to thin models and they think
that that's normal for them to be thin
and that could cause them to go into
anorexia bulimia or or unhealthy
practices because they think being thin
is a norm whil else being healthy and
being normal bodied is actually the norm
now what about young boys do you think
that uh celebrities can have an
influence on young boys I think most
definitely
um I think young boys could be
influenced in a way materialistically
like they would want the big car that
you know the celebrities drive and they
want the bling and they want all the
cool gadgets and tools that there are
out there and it could make boys realize
that you know materialistic things are
the only way to
happiness now what about uh public
opinion
how might celebrities be used to
influence public opinion celebrities are
used actually to like if you can see uh
P the protection of the endangered
animals
um they use celeberties to get to the
public there's like this promotion where
they get celebrities to go naked to show
that you know
animals you know are stripped especially
like seals and uh foxes and all that for
their fur and you know it strikes a cord
because it's a celebrity oh that
person's doing that let's look at the
poster oh what's the message oh okay I
get it no yeah well thank you very much
that's the end of the speaking test
thank you very much